[Music]
hi everyone and welcome to pola
the new name for our
youtube channel and it is our business
name so the first video we're gonna do
under the new name is salt and straws
honey lavender
totally the wrong time of year to do
this as is now october and lavender is a
springtime flower but a
shirt happens
for the lavender part take your honey
and water and bring it up to a nice boil
stir it occasionally and then when it's
really boiling turn the heat off and add
your lavender flowers
let that steep for a minimum of four
hours ideally overnight
when it's ready strain it through a
cheesecloth and then keep it in the
fridge
[Music]
so this is salt and straws standard ice
cream base put your corn syrup and milk
in a pan and slowly bring that up to a
warm temperature no boiling no steaming
and then add in your sugar which has got
your xanthan gum mix in it already and
your milk powder get it all nicely
combined take it off the heat and then
add in your cream put that in the fridge
until you're ready to use it
[Music]
once everything's chilled in the fridge
take it out
i've strained the lavender mix again but
you don't have to
put that mix into your ice cream base
and finally add your purple food
coloring if you choose to use it
now salt and straw say that you don't
have to use it but obviously it gives a
lovely color when it's ready
pop it in your machine to churn this
took 11 and a half minutes in my machine
but it can take whatever it might take
in whatever machine you use
when it comes up to consistency take it
out put it in your tub and store it in
the freezer
[Music]
look at that tub
we were talking about the tub and you
know the whole beehive thing there's
loads of funky bee hives out there
so i'd love to have a beehive at some
point
there's our top of our new tub new logo
it's all good honey lavender nice easy
one to make
i mean this recipe is all over the
internet so if you don't want to follow
this one you can follow any of the
others they'll be identical but we're
just going to get some scooped straight
out into the bowl and see what this
tastes like
[Music]
i mean first things first
i'm not a massive fan of the whole
floral tasting thing but
loads of people asked us to make this
ice cream it's i mean even salt and
straw say it's it's the most most
spit it out it is their most divisive
flavor so
it's you know it's a marmite thing you
love it you hate it
i mean i can't even stand palma violet
so
let's just see how this goes shall we
[Music]
i mean texture wise it's great
salt straw obviously
you know they know what they know what
they're doing they know what they're
talking about as far as ice cream is
concerned flavor-wise it's not for me it
does just you know tastes like when
you're a young kid and you go to your
grandparents or great grandparents house
and you go fishing around and you find
something in the sock drawer that's been
there for 25 years this is what it
smells like
it's um maybe that's just me
it's a bit too perfumey
for me
but
if you like these kind of flavors these
floral
type of things you know the palma
violets i mean violet is actually a
stronger flavor than lavender
but it these are along the same lines
texturized it's great it's really smooth
there's there's no ice in there
whatsoever
the flavor is actually you know in
comparison to honey i guess it's all
quite balanced the honey comes through
after for me
but there's lots of different types of
honey some really strong ones we had one
that we made a honey based ice cream
with but that was so strong overpowered
any other flavor that you mix those ice
creams with so just use a honey that is
medium flavor otherwise you're going to
get a bit out of balance but
all in all it's a nice easy one to try
maybe wait until lavender is in season
but other than that
go for it it's a good one
if you like
plants
anyway thanks for watching don't forget
to like and subscribe and we'll see you
next week
[Music]